大家早上好
So good morning everyone
我的名字是斯巴达辛斯基
my name is spartanshinski
我谨欢迎您介绍
and i would like to welcome you on the presentation of the
这是一个免费的动画对话系统
Which is a free sinematic dialogue system
我提到要找一位导演，否则那就是一个遗憾
I i mentiontaking a director or that's a the pregret
在我另一天
And on my other's day
我在引擎上编写开发我们内部的代码
I write code developing our in house at engine
正如你所看到的，在过去
As you can see , in the past
我当时从事水上游戏工作
i was working on the water game years
ERROR
And currently working on a new game
几英镑二七十七
several pound twenty seventy seven
去
Go
好的，首先
Okay , first
我想向您展示我们在程序员中的精彩对话
I'd like to show you our awesome dialogue in programmers
动画师 qa 和 anuh 以及程序员和设计师
Animators qa and anuh and programmers and designers
因为我今天要向你展示的一切
because everything i'm going to show you today
是如何来和工作的结果
Is the result of how will come and work
对于那些还没有免费玩《未来》的人
And for those of you who have not played the future free
让他用游戏来展现英国风情
let him british show with the game
我将要谈论的是
I will be talking about
好的
Okay
那么微信是什么
So what is the wechat
这是一个开放世界的角色扮演游戏，它不仅仅是作为今天所谓的元素的商店
Which is an open world rpg with no only as store as its called element for today
玩绳索故事、国王等等
Play cord stories , a king and everything
每个游戏系统均已构建
Every game system is built
这个原则或者说向玩家传达故事的主要工具是对话
This principle or the main tool for communicating story to players is dialogue
因为对话让我们能够向玩家提供选择
Because dialogue allow us to present choices to players
然而，提出一个有意义的选择要困难得多
However , it's much harder to present a meaningful choice
使用 oniggamlay 这就是电影对话对我们来说很可爱的原因
Using oniggamlay that's the reason why cinematic dialogue was a cute for us
ERROR
To make a meaningful choice
请玩家主粉丝情感依恋
Please player master fan emotional attachment
为了让这件事发生
For this to happen
ERROR
We need to build the connection between the players at the game characters
建立这种联系可以通过加拿大工作等有价值的方式来实现
Building such a connection can be achieved in valuable ways like canada work
面部表情或一般非语言交流
Facial expression or general nonverbal communication
按照那里的规则对决
According to the rule showdown there
如此简单的手势和服装就能告诉我们
So simple gesture and clothes up can tell us
超过许多台词的对话
More than many lines of the dialogue
好的
Okay
所以如果电影内容对我们来说如此重要
So if cinematic content is so important for us
我可以创造每一个对话，对吧
I metors can create every single dialogue , right
不幸的是，这是不可能的
Unfortunately , it wouldn't be possible
我们必须重新创造，呃
We had to create over , uh
三十五小时的，呃，基因内容
Thirty five hours of , uh , geninematic content
所以我们需要一支番茄大军
So we would require an army of ftomato
我们根本就没有
we simply didn't have
此外，切割的生产成本昂贵
Additionally , cutting are expensive to produce
每次切割都需要经过培训的 mocup 课程
Every cutting requires a educated mocup session
以及许多天的动画师工作
And many days of animator work
正如你在图片上看到的
As you can see on the picture
你必须创造超过一千四百个对话
You had to create over fourteen hundred dialogues
ERROR
So it's insane number for a small team
那么解决方案是什么
So what was the solution
实施的解决方案是一个对话系统，使我们能够创建电影内容
The solution implemented was a dialogue system that allowed us to create cinematic content
仅使用灵长类资产，例如构建 Leggo Beks 的东西
Using only primate assets like building something of leggo beks
我将向您展示一个简单的例子
I will show you on the simple example
所以一方面你可以看到定制
So the one side you can see a custom
每次剪辑都是从模型开始的
Every cutting started as a mokup session
简单地说一个主题需要一次 mocup 会话
And simply speaking one catheme takes one mocup session
另一方面，达拉斯是由通用件制成的
Dallas on other hand are made from generic pieces
ERROR
So from the same set of building blocks
我们可以创造很多对话
We can create many dialogues
这就是关键
And this is the key
这种方法的情况要好得多
this approach is case much better
而且成本效益高
And it's cost effective
当然还值得一提的是
of course it's also worth to mention that
当你已经完成了所有的scremate资产时
When you have all the scremate assets already done
每个人都可以创建对话
Everyone can create a dialogue
你不需要知道我的情感构建者或最大
You don't need to know that my emotion builder or max
您可以打开小或并创建资产
You can open little or and create assets
即使我没有电影背景
And even i without an ecinematic background
几乎所有的例子都做了
Made all almost all examples
你将会看到这个演示
You will see this presentation
好的，讲讲分级习惯
Okay , rapping up classing customs
动画师制作的经典剪辑是我们可以在对话中使用的构建块之一
classic cutting made by animator is one of our building block that we can use in the dialogue
通常 ktine 在独特的场景中是必要的，否则
and usually ktine was necessary in unique scenarios that otherwise
仅使用通用部件很难构建
Would be hard to build using only generic pieces
所以视频块的剪切看起来更像这样
So cuts in viding blocks looks more like this
就像一件适合特殊情况的独特作品
Like a unique piece for special situation
发展之初
At the beginning of the development
我们有一个面向未来的对话系统。二
We had a dialogue system for the future . two
这是相当简单的情感角色，具有完整的肢体动作或理想的动画
It was rather simple emotional characters with a full bodigesture or ideal animation
摄像机的移动仅限于简单的剪切
The camera movement was limited to simple cuts
当你将它与海关进行比较时
When you compare it to the customs
达洛克的活力较差，质量较低
dallocks were less dynamic and lower quality
为了未来的自由
For the future free
你想要对话有同样的感觉，头上的伤口
You want to dialogue to have the same feeling , the cuts in head
同等数量的质量
The same amount of quality
相同量的抛光剂
The same amount of polish
首先让我们看看我们的最终结果是什么样的
So first let's see how our our final result looks like
夏日我爱你哈哈哈哈哈
现在为我们的特殊客人提供特别款待
And now a special treat for our special guests
巫师杰洛特和他迷人的搭档陈音乐家
The witcher geralt and his enchanting partner chan musicians
为这对恩爱夫妻准备的可爱的东西
Something lovely for the loving couple
最后为我们的爱的拥抱音乐
at last music for our loving embrace
来吧，闪耀吧，是时候我发现我浪漫的一面了
Come shining it's time i discovered my romantic side
哦，你很擅长这个
oh you're rather good at this
好的
Okay
所以总结一下我们的鬼脚
So summarize our ghost for the witter feet
ERROR
We wanted to create unique cinematic content
仅大规模使用通用构建块
Using only generic building blocks on a massive scale
在我只解释所有细节之前
And before i would only explain all the details
我想向你展示大局
I'd like to show you the big picture
呃对话是如何放置在游戏中的
How the , uh dialogue is placed within the game
ERROR
So we start to restore
一旦战斗分裂成任务
Once the fight in splitting into the quests
每个任务都有它的一部分
and every quest there's a part of it
ERROR
Quests are implemented in our viooscyptic language that contains a lot of nodes for different needs
其中一个节点是对话
And one of the nodes is a dialogue
请注意，开始对话
Note that starts a dialogue
最后的 itDialoguitor 提供了从头到尾处理对话所需的所有工具
And final it dialoguitor provides all necessary tools for working with dialogues from the beginning to the end
最后的门廊
The final porch
好的
Okay
现在我们来谈谈细节
So now let's talk about deta
因为对话系统相当复杂
Because dialog system is quite complex
我想向您展示单一对话的流程
I'd like to show you the the pipeline of single dialogue
ERROR
So you can see how it works step by step
所以我们有编剧、对话设计师和后期制作
So we have writers quest dialog designers and post production
所以我们从编剧部门开始
So we we start with the writers department
每个对话都以 tt 爬行开始
Every dialogue start as a tt crept
剧本是在对话编辑器的视觉效果中编写的
The screen play is written in our visual in our dialogue editor
而此时
And at this point
它分为几个部分和选择
It's split into the sections and choices
所以我们有了图的基本存储结构
So we have the basic storage structure as a graph
保持这个，呃，结构井井有条很重要
It's important to keep this , uh , structure organized
因为 deluxin nutral 真的很复杂
Because deluxin nutral can be really complicated
所以图图方法非常好
So graph graph approach scares very nice
ERROR
I also prepared this way as passed to the , uh
任务设计师定义了诸如何时应该播放对话之类的感觉
Quest quest designers defined feelings like when the dialogue should be played
演员都有谁
Who are the actors
并在什么情况下
And in what appreences
ERROR
And finally where the dialogue should be played
重要的是要说的是
It's important to say that
我们有猎魔人的故事不仅仅意味着对话
No ina story that we have the witcher means no only a dialogue
是如何做到的。 the quest designers are responsible for adding flow conditions
How it's done . the quest designers are responsible for adding flow conditions
您可以在幻灯片上看到的蓝色音符控制通过，呃，电报的信号流
The blue notes you can see on the slide that controls the signal flow through the , uh , stelegraph
ERROR
So previous play decisions have impact on store progression
同时
And at the same time
对话可以控制游戏
Dialogue can control the game
使用跳过节点的游戏状态
The gamely state by using the skip node
或者通过设置游戏fg数据库
Or by setting the game fg database
所以游戏和故事之间的交流是双向的
So the communication between the game and the story goes both ways
好的
Okay
因此，一旦新闻设计师下载了对话，对话设计师就进来了
So once press designers are download the dialogue dialog designers came in
ERROR
They create a visual side of the things
这是主要部分
And this is the major part
所以仔细看看这里发生了什么
So take a closer look what's happening here
设计师的那些
That of designers
我喜欢电影导演
i like movie directors
主要通过时间线
The primary through the timeline
类似于vivideo编辑软件的doorks
The doorks similarly to vivideo editing software
所以时间线的左边与诗句的声音相关
So the left of the timeline is tied to the voice of verse
泰国也举办活动
And thailand holds events
事件代表玩家的动作
Events represent actions on the players
还有 octos 物品或灯光等
And octos items or light and so on
并且您有很多满足不同需求的活动
And you have a lot of events for different needs
还有更多活动可以参加
What's more events can be joined
插值、加权或训练
Interpolated , weighted or traint
所以它转移到一个简单的系统，同时又非常灵活
So it transferred to a simple system that at the same time it's quite flexible
所以为了百分百清楚
So to make it one hundred percent clear
这是一个简单的例子
That was a simple example
所以在这种情况下我们可以看到两种颜色
so in this case we can see the two colors
我们可以添加像看这样的简单事件
We can add like the simple event like look at
或者我们可以像他们一样添加
Or we can add like them
持续时间事件，例如动画
Duration events , for example , uanimation
做吧
Do it
每个事件都可以修改
Every event can be modified
所以我们可以改变事件的持续时间
So we can change the duration of the event
所以动画速度变慢
so the animation is slowdown
或者你可以拍拍开头
Or you can clap the beginning
锁定事件的开头
Clamp the beginning of the event
所以混合因素动画会有所不同
So the blend in factor animation will do different
同样的方式我们可以控制身体动画
The same way we can control the the body animation
我们可以控制面部动画
we can control the facial animations
或者任何物体，并且可以随时在外观细节中移除
Or any object and that in any time can be removed in the look a detail
假设您想将其移出一点
So let's say you would like to move it get out a little bit
正如我提到的，我们可以插入事件
As i mentioned we can interpolate the event
所以让我们针对这个案例这样做
So let's do this for this case
你就有了超级简单的动画
and you have that super simple animation
好吧，电影内容要求蒸汽必须接地气，游戏世界
Okay , cinematic content demands that the steam has to be grounded , the game world
因此，由于这种对话，设计师想要了解dialo周围的环境
So because of this dialogue , designers wanted to be aware of the dialoe surroundings
所以你添加了可以添加对话的功能
So you added feature that you can add it dialogue
不仅在空旷的地方
not only inside the empty
您可以在幻灯片上看到对话预览
And dialogue preview you can see on the slide
但也体现在最终的比赛层面上
But also on the final game level
所以多亏了这个
So thanks to this
他们精心设计了泰勒省略了粒子分配的内容
They crafted taylor omit it content for the particle allocation
当然，让我们看看它是如何工作的
Of course , let's see how it works
我们有同样的例子
We have the same example
别来了时间线
Don't come the timeline
只需按下一个按钮
And just passing one button
您可以在最终游戏关卡中输入相同的对话
You can enter the same dialogue on the final game level
现在你可以看到最终的光照阴影
So now you can see the final lighting shadows
呃，角色周围的所有道具
Uh , all the props around the characters
那些非常有用的功能
Those very useful feature
因此，时间线是我们的游乐场，您可以快速有效地放置事件并创建内容
So timeline was our playground that you can put events and create content in fast and efficient way
甚至基本方法也易于使用且易于扩展
And even base approach is easy to use and easy to extent
所以我认为新功能对程序员来说不是问题
So i think new feature wasn't an issue for programmers
正如您将在演示的下一部分中看到的
And as you will see in the next part of the presentation
几乎每一个视觉基本对话都是由时间线控制的
Almost every visual elementary dialogue was controlled by timeline
好的
Okay
现在我们知道时间是什么了
So now we know what the timing is
那么我们来谈谈如何找到内容
So let's talk about how we can fd with content
那么我们来谈谈 dao 设计器的工作流程
So let's talk about dao designers workflow
首先是对话框设置
The first thing is the dialog set
对话框集是一个包含字符列表的模板
Dialog set is a template that contains the list of the characters
有关他们的一些基本信息，例如职位
With some basic information about them like position
情绪状态、帖子等
Emotional state , posts and so on
因此，对话集就像对话状态的快照，我们可以在必要时横向使用或倾向于使用它
So dialogue set is like a snapshot of a dialogue state that we can laterally use or tend to if necessary
下一步是生成器
The next step is the generator
这听起来很疯狂，特别是对艺术家来说
It sounds crazy , especially for the artist
但我们确实通过代码生成dio
But we do generate dios by code
一般目的是使时间线与基本事件相匹配
General purpose is to fit timeline with basic events
所以它创建了对话的第一遍
So it creates the first pass of the dialogue
看
Look
设计师发现修复或修改现有事件比对每个事件进行检测要快得多
Designers found out that it's much faster to fix or modify existing events than to insect every event
每一次或每一个角色
Every time or every character
Genetor 工作得非常好，以至于一些不太重要的对话
Genetor works so well that some of the less important dialogues
人手可能会严重碰触
Could be badly touched by the human hand
那么数据如何工作需要三种不同类型的输入
So how it works data to requires three different types of inputs
演员信息
The information about the actors
所以或多或少的对话集
so more or less dialogue set
像电影摄影那样的一套规则
The set of rules like cinema ca matography
就像一百八十规则是什么
Like what does the one hundred eighty rule
或者该机构做什么？
Or what does the establishment sht
最后是从配音中提取的数据
And finally the extracted data from voicovers
所以我不想用细节来咬你
So i don't want to bite you with details
但重要的是我们使用mfcc
But what's important is that we use mfcc
我倾向于从画外音中产生市场或口音
I oridden to generate markets or accents from the voiceovers
这样稍后您就可以将事件和动画与声音相匹配
So later you can match the the events and animation with the sound
所以我们把一整天的时间都投入到发电机上
So we put to put all the day time to the generator
它会生成像相机这样的事件
And it generates events like cameras
嗯，面部动画板发射
U um , facial animation board emissions
他们看着
And they look at
当然，让我们看看它是如何工作的
So of course let's see how it works
玛丽娜女士，我们可以谈谈利维亚的加勒特吗
Madam marina , can we talk garrett of rivia
蒲公英告诉我们很多关于你的事
Dandelions told us so much about you
他和你在一起吗
Is he with you
不
No
但我希望尽快把他带回来
But i hope to bring him back soon
这里说说doodoo h
Here to talk about doodoo h
让我们在剧院后面我的宿舍里说话吧，那里不会受到打扰
Let's speak in my quarters at the back of the theatre will be undisturbed there
好的
Okay
您可以连续生成一次吗
And can you can generate generated one more time in row
炉子等特别准备的
the stove seeds and like special prepared
玛丽娜女士，我们可以谈谈利维亚的阁楼吗
Madam marina , can we talk garret of rivia
蒲公英告诉我们很多关于你的事
Dandelions told us so much about you
他和你在一起吗
Is he with you
不，但我希望尽快把他带回来
No , but i hope to bring him back soon
这里说说dudm
Here to talk about dudm
让我们在我的宿舍里说话吧
Let's speak in my quarters
在剧院的后面
At the back of the theatre
那里将不受打扰
Will be undisturbed there
好的，现在我还有一个稍微不同的设置示例
Okay , and now i have one more example of a little bit different settings
这个视频真的很长
This video is really long
所以我想向您展示第一次感染
So i would like to show you on the the first intection
稍后您可以在附赠幻灯片部分观看
And later you can watch it in the bonus slide section
我一个人进去
I'll go in alone
你知道你会呆在外面
You know you'll stay outside
我不能让你一个人走
I can't let you go alone
不管你发生什么事，达雷尔，别扯下我的头
Anything happens to you , darrell don't rip my head off
必须有人保护我们的撤退
Someone must secure our retreat
必然会有一场斗争
There's bound to be a struggle
事情可能会变得激烈
Things could get intense
我们需要快速逃离
We'll need to flee fast
消失在人群中
Disappear in the crowd
好的
Okay
所以同上拯救了很多设计师
So ditto saved a lot of designers st
当然，基因场景的质量没有定制的那么高
Of course the quality of genetic scene is not as high as a cucustom made custine
但这不是基因遗传
But it wasn't genetal g
使用这个工具，您可以非常快速地生成不同的对话变体
Using this tool , you can generate very fast different dialogue variations
所以如果你不喜欢当前的，呃，对话实例，也没有问题
So if you don't like current , uh , dialogue instance , there's no problem
只需按一个按钮
Just press one button
然后你就有了新的，呃，迭代
And you have new , uh , iteration
这样以后你就可以修复你不喜欢的事情
So later you can fix things you don't like
只要你有时间，呃
As long as you have time for , uh
或者只要有必要
Or as long as it's necessary
下一个对话框是手动完成的
Next dialog is posessed by hand
第一个对话设计师改进了指挥官的工作
First dialogue designers improve the commander work
因此，存储有关相机的一些基本信息的对话
So the dialogues that stores some basic information about the cameras
所以相同的镜头可以重复使用
So the same shots can be reused
这确保了凝聚力
Which ensures cohesion
还可以为特殊情况创建自定义镜头
It's also possible to create custom shots for special cases
所以用偶数插值法
So with even uh , interpolation method
设计师可以创建有趣的镜头，平衡肩上对话摄像机的效果
designers can create interesting shots that balanced come on over the shoulder dialog cameras
接下来是时间，呃
Next is time it's time for , uh
我认为性格对我们来说特别重要
Character ido i think are especially important for us
因为为以后的角色表演有类似的基础
because there are like foundation for future character performance
所以我们有将近三十五
So we had almost thirty five
根据角色类型不同的理想动画
Different ideal animations by character type
所以这意味着每个女人三十五
So it means thirty five per woman
每人三十五块，矮人等等
Thirty five per man , dwarf and so on
另外，我们有不同的羽绒服或不同的姿势，比如坐着站着的亲戚
Additionary , we had different eiders or different poses like sitting standing kin
所以每个偶像都是从社会地位的自由类别中选出的
So each idol is chosen from free categories of social status
情绪化的状态和帖子
Emotionalized state and posts
所以它很好地映射到重组中
So it maps nicely into a restructure
例如，高侵略性地位
for example , high aggressive standing
或高度激进的坐姿
Or high gressive sitting
好的，下一步我看看
Okay next step i look at
Look at 是我们为 delo 设计师提供的最强大的动画工具之一
Look at are one of our most powerful animation tool for delo designers
所以解释我们的解决方案很重要，其中有两个
So it's important to explain our solution in which are two
我们通过旋转 toral 的头部来使用程序来查看它的工作原理
We use procedual look at it worked by rotating the head of toral
通过在代码中设置愤怒
By setting anger in code
所以这是常见的解决方案
So it's common solution
但它也不适合更复杂的事情，比如坐着躺着
But it doesn't go well with more complicated either like sitting on laying
那么其中哪些是免费的
So in which are free
动画师希望完全控制姿势
Animators wanted to have full control over poses
所以我们决定实现基于本地动画
So we decided to implement animation based local
较少的前极性溶液
The less propolar solution
对于输入来说非常有趣
As is quite interesting for the input for the
算法是一个动画。我们看看装腔作势的人
Algorit is an animation . we look at posers
例如，我们在一秒内有一个姿势
And for instance we have one pose by a second
动画师可以根据需要创造任意数量的姿势
Animmer can create as many poses as needed
所以即使像站立这样简单的柱子也没关系
So it doesn't matter if the post is simple like standing
ERROR
Or it's more complicated like seating
所以在这种情况下角色接触地面
So in this case character touches the ground
这不是问题，因为每个姿势都是由动画师创建的
It's not an issue because every single pose is created by animator
所以关键是我们修改整个姿势
So the keys fact that we modify the whole pose
不仅是头部等少数骨头
Not only the the few bones like head or also
所以多亏了这个
So thanks to this
我们不需要像 uber 那样写
We don't need to write like the uber
查看支持每种特殊情况（例如站立座椅膝盖）的 King Code
Look at king code that supports every special case like standing seating knee
但是您可以为每种特殊情况编写非常简单的代码
But you can write a very simple code and for every special case
我们可以专门看看动画
We can have a special look at animation
所以这个解决方案是全数据驱动的
So this solution is full full data data driven
而且很有艺术家风格
And is very artist strandy
那么它是如何运作的
So how it works
正如我提到的算法的输入和查看姿势的动画
As i mentioned the input for algorithms and animmation of look at poses
因此，对于我们计算的每个姿势或
So for every pose we calculate or where the
呃，看看目标是
Uh , look at target is
所以我们稍后会得到这个
So here we get this later
记住所有这些点并在角色周围创建一个三网格
recollect all this points and create one three mesh around the character
有一次当你从对话中找到目标时
And you one time when you have the target from the dialogue
所以这个黄色盒子
So this yellow box
黄色框位置投影到该流网格上
The yellow box position is projected onto this stream mesh
给我们一个三角形
Giving us like one triangle
从这个三角形我们有
From this one triangle we have
呃，免费网络票
Uh , free web tices
这意味着自由地看姿势
It means free look at poses
就像将这三个姿势以适当的，呃，比例混合在一起
Like blending these three poses with proper , uh , proportion
使用 proo si 坐标为我们提供适当的变形
Using proo si codinates gives us proper deformation
我们有两个级别
And we have two levels
呃，对于外观，对于像全身或头部这样的角色
Uh , for the look at , for characters like full body or head on
所以这意味着你必须创建，嗯
So it means that you had to create , um
致每一位看动画的奉献者
To the dedicate that look at an animation by every single either
其中一些非常简单
Some of them are very simple
其中一些几乎是免费的
Some of them were almost free
六十
Sixty
也可以创建，呃，看看，嗯，冰
It's also possible to create , uh , look at for , um , ice
但它是为面部动画链接完成的
But it's done for the facial animation link
现在让我们看看最后的表演
So now let's see the final act
所以总结一下基于动画的从代码的角度来看它非常简单
So summarize the animation based look at it's very simple from code point of view
完整的数据驱动解决方案
Full of data driven solution
就像动画师一样，呃，可以完全控制姿势
Like animators , uh , have full control of over poses
实际上这并不耗时
And in practice it's not time consuming
因为他们只需创造姿势
Because they have to create only poses
不像他们的完整动画
Not like their full animation
因此，使用像 my amotion via 这样的软件非常简单快捷
So using software like my amotion via it's quite easy and fast to do
因为它是基于动画，呃，资源
And because it's based on the animation , uh , resources
程序员可以离线使用这些资产
Programmers can allize those assets offline
并且在一时间
And in one time
您可以创建许多有趣的变体，就像所有扩展一样
You can create many interesting variations , like all extensions
呃，就像过程转换一样
Uh , like procedure transitions
第二次情绪或超过喊叫
Second emotion or over the shouts
好的
Okay
那么让我们从卢卡斯转向动画
So let's move from lucas to animations
我们有超过两千四百个专门的对话动画，就像这么多的内容
We had over twenty four hundred dededicated dialogue animations like so much content
你马赫但我们必须用这个数字除以数字
You machbut we have to divide this number by number
呃，字符类型
Uh , of character types
情绪状态、姿势等
Emotional state , poses , and so on
所以最后只剩下一堆，呃，手势
So it's end up that there's only a bunch of , um , gestures
但每一个eded
But every single eded
此外，我们还必须统计大多数员工
Moreover , we have to count most stas
出色地
Well
有的对话复杂，内容丰富
Some of them had sophisticated dialogues with a lot of content
所以因为这个限制
So because of this limits
我们必须尽可能依赖重用动画
We have to rely on reusing animations wherever possible
我们继续练习吧
Let's go on practice
即使像迪士尼这样最伟大的公司也这么做了
And even the greatest ones like like disney did it
所以在未来的对话系统中
So in future dialogue system
其他动画可以作为正常的替代或覆盖来播放
Other animation can be played as a normal aldative or override
我们可以等待或屏蔽
We can wait down or mask out
设置骨架的部分
Set the part of the skeleton
整个动画片段可以由用户定义的曲线控制
The whole animation clip can be controlled by the user defined curves
所以所有这些简单的操作给了设计师很大的自由度
So all these simple operations gives a lot of freedom to designers
所以我将通过一个简单的例子在汤上重申这一点
So i'm going to restate this on the soup on a simple example
所以我们假设您想在坐姿中使用站立姿势的手势
so let's assume you'd like to use ugesture with standing pose for sitting case
所以在时间线的第一部分
So on the first part of the timeline
您可以通过站立姿势看到站立情况
You can see the standing either with standing gesture
时间线的第二部分正在使用，呃，ida
On the second part of the timeline is useating , uh , ida
所以你只需复制支付，嗯，手势
So you just copy pays the , um , the gesture
当然不行。是的
Of course it doesn't work . yeah
但我们可以把这个动画转换成盛大的时间加法
but we can convert this animation into the additive in grand time
所以现在好多了
So now it's much better
但你仍然可以在玻璃腿上看到一些文物
But still you can see some artifacts on the glass legs
所以使用掩蔽错误权重
So using the masking goof weights
我们可以选择骨架的设置部分
We can select the set up part of the skeleton
所以让我们调整这部分
So let's adaptable the part
好的，现在好多了
Okay , and now it's much better
史蒂夫
Steve
质量不如专用的delec动画高
The quality is not as high as a dedicated delec animation
但正如你所看到的，我们做到了
But as you saw , we did it
我们在几秒钟内就完成了
We did it in seconds
我们很多动画都是这样使用的
And we are used a lot of animation this way
对话动画系统的下一个测试功能是控制谎言
The next testing feature in dialog animation system is control lie
我们在 sults in maker 中找到了此功能的灵感
We found and inspiration for this feature in sults in maker
这对我来说就像是很棒的软件
Which is like amazing software for me
能够在编辑器中为特殊情况创建姿势
Being able to create poses within the editor for special cases
赋予设计师很大的权力
Gives a lot of power to designers
我的意思是喜欢设计师而不是动画师
I mean like to designers not animatoes
因为有了控制装置
Because thanks to the control rig
每个人都可以在对话 itto 中创建自定义内容
everyone can create custom content within the dialogue itto
因此，我们主要将它们用于免费案例来创建自定义帖子
So we use them mostly for free cases to create a custom post
在实践中我们不会使用那么多，因为这很耗时
In practice we don't use that much because it's time consuming
所以主要用于最终细节
So mostly it was used for final details
就像在头部调整手上的手指一样
Like during the head adjusting the fingers on hands
这个节目已经出来了
This program is out
所以我不认为你对此看得太多
So i don't don't you look at this too much
好的，接下来是手势修正
Okay , next is correction for gestures
很有趣
It's quite interesting
那么我们来分析一下
So let's analyse it
对于本例，我们有两个角色
For this case we have two characters
你想为警卫添加像我和你一样的手势
And you would like to add gesture like me and you for the guard
所以在这种情况下，一切都很完美
So in this scenario , like everything works perfectly
但让我们稍微努力一下
but let's move the effort that a little bit
所以现在这个手势并不能表现出情绪
So now this gesture like doesn't feat emo
所以我们有两个选择
So we have two options
我们可以旋转防护罩
We can rotate the guart
但我们假设在这种情况下你不能这样做
But let's assume you can not do this in this case
或者我们可以应用集合
Or we can apply the collection
所以我们将它们插入时间轴上的帖子键
so we insert them post key on the timeline
并用它来控制
And use it control
你可以，呃
You can the , uh
转动手和头
Rotate the hand and head
所以当我们将这个后期修正与动画联系起来时
So when we link this post correction with the animation
修正申请的适当时间协议
The proper time aggree applied for the correction
是的，所以现在好多了
yeah , so now it's much better it
好的，就像单一手势一样
Okay , and like on single gestures
您也可以对此进行更正
You can apply corrections on this as well
大多数情况下，我们使用它们来通过道德问题来修复网格，就像这个例子一样
And mostly we use them for fixing mesh by ethetic issue like on this example
所以最终我们为相反的预设创建了一个小型数据库
So it's end up that we create a small database for contrary , uh , presets
所以我们可以在几秒钟内解决这样的问题
So we can fix issues like this in seconds
面部控制也进行了类似的改造
And facial control reworks similarly
这样你就可以创建自定义的，呃，姿势
So you could create the custom , uh , poses
您可以对手势或其他应用应用更正
You can apply the corrections for gestures or for others
所以重复一下我自己
So to repeat myself
我想向您展示控制面板
I would like to show you the , the control panel
所以这次不是，呃，骨头
So this time instead of , uh , bones
我们有，呃，大量的操纵杆来应对不同的，呃，面部变形
We have , uh , plenty of joysticks for different , uh , facial deformations
好的
Okay
因此，请使用使用管道的动画来对抗装备
So conter rigs with animation that are using pipeline
给设计师很大的自由度
Gives a lot of freedom to designers
他们可以在对话框中创建自定义内容
They can create custom content within the dialog
Itor 就像点播它是呃
Itor like on demand it's uh
这非常重要，因为日程安排很紧
This is very important because with tight schedules
你要么能够创造一些东西，要么能够在几秒钟内混合一些东西
You either be able to create something or mix something seconds
或者你必须离开并润色对话并转到下一个
Or you have to leave and polish dialogue and move to the next one
好的
Okay
放置所有物品和道具是对话设计师呃工作的最后阶段
Placing all items and , and props is the last stage of dialogue designers , uh , work
正如我向你展示的那样
So as i showed you
每个stin元素都可以一次移动
Every stin element can be moved at a time
我们可以使用，呃
We can use , uh
甚至是应用简单动画的插值方法或更复杂的工艺
Even the polation methods or busier crafts to apply simple animations
当我们有很多道具的时候
When we have a lot of props
我们可以，呃，彼此相连
And we can attach , uh , each to each other
或者除了彼此之间或者当你有动画时
Or other than to each other or when you have the animations
这些可以同步
Those can be synchronized
所以所有这些小事都帮助我们创造，嗯
So all these little things help us to create , um
让 Steam 扎根游戏世界的细节
Details that rooted steam within the game world
这就是对话框设计者的工作流程
And that was the dialog designers workflow
现在你知道对话的视觉方面是如何完成的了
So now you know how the visual side side of the dialogue is done
所以我要总结一下这部分
So i'm going to summarize this part
并向您展示进度截图
And show you the progress shots
呃，其中一个，呃，游戏中的对话
Uh , of the one of this , uh , dialogue from the game
所以我们可以在示例中看到它是如何工作的
So we can see how it works on the examples
所以首先我们有一个空的时间线
So first we have the empty timeline
我们录制了画外音
We've recorded voiceovers
你会用生成器来创建第一遍对话吗
Will you generator to create the first pass of dialogue
看
Look
你在那儿
You're there
米洛弗就是一个词。不耐烦
Mirover was a word . impatient
快点
Faster
哦，没什么
Oh nothing
很快就到了
Be there soon
好的，接下来我们从第一阶段进入下一个阶段
Okay , next we move from the first stage to the next one
所以设计师改进了相机、动画和动画
so designers improve the cameras , iders and animations
罗宾先生想要一个不耐烦的词
You there mr robin wants a word impatient
旧的 哦 没什么 很快就会出现
old basted oh nothing be there soon
好的，最后阶段
Okay , and the final stage
所以最后的打磨
So the final polish
呃，面部图像修正和所有细节
uh , facial imation corrections and all the details
你在那里，罗弗先生，这个词是什么？
You there mr rover what's a word
不耐烦的老混蛋，但很快就没有什么了
impatient old bastard but nothing be there soon
好的
Okay
像这样简单的事情需要几分钟才能完成
Simply thing like this took a few minutes to be done
即使对于像我这样的人
Even for guys like me
好的
Okay
所以一开始我就说过必须创造一千四百个对话
So at the beginning i said that had to create fourteen hundred dialogues
所以我们已经有了构建块
So we've got the building blocks
我们可以生成对话，或者我们可以混合现有的，呃，通用片段
We can generate the dialogue or we can mix existing , uh , generic pieces
但有哪些特殊情况
But what are the special cases
特殊的外壳制作，独特，手工制作，与custin类似
Special case made that like unique , handmade and similar to custin
我们的第二个目标是什么
What was our second goal
这段对话应该有和卡斯汀一样的感觉
That dialogue should have the same feeling the custin has
现在让我们看看如何在 devia 的 dialuate 详细信息中创建自定义案例
So now let's see how we can create custom cases within the dialuate detail for devia
这次我想安
This time i would like to ann
呃，从游戏一开始就充满了蒸汽
Uh , the steam from the beginning of the game
从序幕传近球
From the prologue passing the close ball
首先让我们看一下对话
So first let's see the dialogue
我们去热烈欢迎它吧
Let's go give it a warm welcome
等待
Wait
做这个
Make this
在汽车游戏中，当你四处奔跑时想要穿过弓可能会派上用场
across bow wanted in a car game while you run around might come in handy
好吧，所以我们对传横球没有特别的兴趣
Okay , so we don't have special animmersion for passing crossball
但我们有一个可以收到钥匙的
But we have one with receiving a key
所以这将是我们的基地
So this will be our base
接下来我们敲击交叉探针并将其连接到手上
Next we pound the crossover probe and attach it to the hand
就像确保交叉适合手
like making sure that the crosswfits to the hand
相机拍摄它完全被剪切
And the camera shot it set cut fully
不要表现出他们错过的太多部分
Not to show their miss much parts
之后我们可以使用控制装置来添加最终细节
And later we can use a control rig for adding final details
就像调整手指和头部一样
Like adjust in the fingers and head
这样就完成了
And this it's done
让我们看看它在最终游戏中的表现如何
So let's see how it works in the final game
我们去热烈欢迎你
Let's go give you a warm welcome
等等等等这个
wait wait this
纸牌游戏中想要的弩
The crossbow wanted in a card game
当你四处奔走时可能会派上用场
While you ran around might come in handy
好的
Okay
因此，能够创造独特的对话对于在广阔的天空中制作它们同样重要
So being able to create unique dialogues is equally important to make them on a massive sky
我们不会将数量置于质量之上
And we do not put quantity over quality
所以每次对话都应该有一些特别的东西
So every dialogue should have something special
这让 splay 对这项研究产生了情感上的依恋
That makes splay feel emotionally attached to the study
现在让我们看一些更复杂的自定义案例示例
So now let's see a little bit more complicated example of the custom cases
哦不，你没有听到我，你不敢吗
oh no you don't hear me don't you dare
请不要这样对我
please don't do this to me
肖尼·杰洛特
Shawny geralt
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here
试图拯救他的妻子
Trying to save his wife
帮帮我，珊妮冷静下来
Help me , shanny calm down
他死了，我确信可以做点什么
He's dead i'm sure something can be done
呃，好吧
Uh , okay
如果你认为这是一个小菜
And if you think it's a custine
不是它还有我们的对话系统
It's not it's still have our dialogue system
什尼·加勒特
Shnny garrett
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here
试图挽救他的生命
Trying to save his life
帮帮我，珊妮冷静下来
Help me , shanny calm down
他死了，我确信可以做点什么
He's dead i'm sure something can be done
呃
Uh
放手吧
let it go
该死的
damn it
无缘无故地关掉
off for nothing
你已经尽力了
you did all you could
谢谢加勒特
thanks garrett
好的
Okay
那么，让我们离开对话设计者，进入下一个，呃，管道步骤，包括制作
So let's leave dialog designers and move to the next , uh , pipeline step , both production
所以当你谈论主题，呃，内容时
So when you talk about thematic , uh , content
我认为考虑到这一点至关重要
I think is crucial element to taking into account
但有时在游戏中我们必须添加灯光
But sometimes in games we have to add light
因为我认为如果没有额外的东西就很难看到发生了什么
Because it's hard to see what's going on without extra , i think
但对于那些故事是国王的时候
But for the which are when stories the king
营造适当情绪的照明语料库，如支持玩具链接
The lighting copus to create a proper mood like support toyal link
所以可以看到定制灯光对这个舞台的影响有多大
So can see how much impact custom lights can that from this stage on this one
所以，但是在日九循环的开放世界游戏中进行对话并不容易
So , but it's not easy to alidialogues in open world game with day and nine cycle
因为我认为总是需要看起来不错
Because i think always needs to look good
没关系
It doesn't matter
就像夜间下雨一样
It's like raining during the night
或者是你周日下午
Or it's u sunday afternoon
那么让我们看看我们如何
So let's see how we
我们如何做
How we do it
我首先把它说得百分百清楚
In which i first to make it like one hundred percent clear
我想分析这个超级简单的例子
I would like to analyze this super simple example
那么我们想添加 , 呃
So let's say would we would like to add , uh
黄灯代表这一步
The yellow light for this , uh , step
所以当你把 , 零灯放在水平面上时
So when you just put the , the zero light on the level
看起来还可以
It seems okay
但是当你改变一天中的某些时间
But when you change part of the day
这个灯已经不适合了
This light doesn't fit anymore
好像太黄太亮了
It's like too yellow and too bright
所以想要有这样的东西
So would like to have something like this
那光有不同的颜色，嗯
That light has different color and , um
一天中不同时段的价值
Value during the different part of the days
但我有同样的感觉，同样的影响
But i have the same feeling , the same impact
好的
Okay
那么它是如何完成的
So how it's done
最后一场比赛
Final game
最终游戏，呃，光照值取决于globlight值
Final game , uh , light value depends on globlight value
这是由闪电艺术家在天气编辑器中设置的
Which is set by lightning artists in the weather editor
乘以对话光
Multiplied by the dialogue light
由对话设计者将事件设置在时间线上
Which set in the event in on the timeline , by the dialogue designers
以及每一个光值
And every light value
每个光属性不是单个值而是一条曲线
Every light property is not a single value but a curve
所以我们可以在一天中的不同时间，呃，有不同的值
So we can have different values of different , uh , part of the day
当然，让我们再次看看它如何作用于真菌
And of course let's see how it works on the fung again
好的
Okay
所以我们认为这是电影内容中非常重要的一部分，呃，内容
So let's think is super important part of the cinematic content , uh , content
即使您必须使用 dani Cycle 创建开放式文字游戏
And even when you have to create like open word game with dani cycle
这个功能不容错过
This feature cannot be missed
我们的解决方案非常适合我们
Our solution works great for us
灯光艺术家创造全球化价值
Lighting artist creates the globalized value
之后每个人都可以为对话创建自定义灯光，而不会破坏最终的游戏外观
And later everyone can create custom lights for dialogue without breaking the final game look
后期制作的第二部分是视觉特效和音效
Second part of the post production are vfx and sound effects
它的工作流程与我之前向您展示的相同
It workflow is the same as i showed you before
所以我们使用时间线来设置特定的事件
So we use timeline to set a specific events
您可以及时移动到不同的事物以获得触摸效果
You can move for touch effects to different things in time
不幸的是我们没有足够的时间来描述一切
Unfortunately we don't have enough time to describe everything
但我相信你明白了
But i'm sure you get the idea
好的
Okay
这就是，嗯，在相互自由的单一对话中
And that was the , um pion of a single dialogue in mutual free
因此，我们让作家寻求对话设计师的工作，就像对话集生成器相机一样
So we have the writers quest dialog designers with their work tho like dialogue set generator cameras
伊德尔斯
Iders
看动画
Look at animations
特殊情况和地理
Special cases and geography
最后进行灯光和效果的后期制作
And finally post production with lighting and the fects
所以我向您展示了所有这些视频和功能
So i showed you all these videos and features
但正如你可以想象的那样，并不是所有事情都那么容易做到
But as you can imagine , not everything was so easy to do
你有几个问题
You have a few problems
其中一些值得分享
And some of them are worf to share
所以它被本地化为十五种语言
So the which is localized into fifteen languages
其中八个有不同的语音版本和付费语言版本
And eight of them had different voice of vers pay language version
所以我告诉你，时间线的长度与我们的声音息息相关
So i show you that the length of the timeline is tied to the voice of us
我们没有使用那个存在
We didn't use that being
所以每一节都有不同持续时间的泛语言版本
So every verse over have different duration pan language version
所以这意味着整个对话可以根据语言版本有不同的日期
So it means that the whole dialogue can have different dation by language version
所以你可以想象一下，使用符号类型的内容
So you can imagine that with symatic type of content
当一切都被小心翼翼地放在时间线上时
When everything is placed carefully on the timeline
所有的手势和同步
And all the gestures and syronize
这是一个现实问题
This is a real issue
所以你不能只改变时间线的持续时间
So you cannot just change the duration of the timeline
因为一切都会不同步
Because everything will be out of sync
所以对我们有用的解决方案就是我们所说的“泰国剥皮”
So the solution working for us was something we called thailand scalling
所以这意味着每个事件都是相对于画外音放置的
So it means that every event is placed relative to voiceover
所以这是关于
So it's about
所以如果语音时间较长
So if voice over its longer
即使会在不同的绝对时间
Even will be in different absolute time
但与配音的比例相同
But in the same proportion to voice over
所以有些甚至，呃
So with some even , uh
具有一些 feh 功能
With some feh features
就像匹配或加入一样，效果非常好
Like even matching or joining , it works really well
所以在这个例子中
So in this example
两个事件都从百分之三十的画外音开始
And both event starts of the thirty percent of the voiceover
但首先，呃，有不同的持续时间
But first over , uh , have different durations
所以这个事件，呃，有不同，嗯
So the event , uh , have different , um
绝对时间和长度
Absolute time and length
那么我们当然要从
So of course let's analyze it from the
以游戏中的例子为例
On the example from the game
所以我们有英文版
So we have the english version
呃
Uh
这需要，呃，十二秒，法语版本
Which takes , uh , to twelve seconds and french version with
这需要，呃，十四秒
Which takes , uh , fourteen seconds
所以这个,这两秒的间隙完全可以在对话中
So this , this two second gap can completely in the dialogue
但由于泰国的规模化，英语应该可以用
But thanks to the thailand scaling , english should work
好的
Okay
那么我们先来看看英文版
So let's check it first , the english version
乌维尔，你认为你是一个猎魔人吗？
Uvel , do you think you are a witcher
一个巫师
A witcher
听说男孩们
Hear that boys
要么帷幔得到了女巫的大丰收
Either valance got a bumper crop of witches
或者这就是在十字路口把我们的孩子们煮熟的混蛋
Or this is the bastard who cook down our boys at the crossroads
现在法语相同的对话和相同的内容
And now french the same dialogue with the same content
好的，现在并排查看
Okay , and now side by side view
所以你可以看到两个实例慢慢地不同步
So you can see that the both instances are slowly are slowly out of sync
但对于每一个实例，一切都很完美
but for every instance everything works perfectly
好的
Okay
接下来是另一个有趣的挑战，我很担心
Next is that interesting challenge was another terrimystic , which i wor
所以我们付出了很多努力来确保对话
So we put a lot of effort to be sure that dialogue
本身在播放或编辑时完全是术语
Itself is completely terministic during playing or editing
所以这意味着你可以随时跳过对话的任何部分
So it means that you can skip any part of the dialogue any time
在下一帧中，所有内容都正确替换
And on the next frame everything replaced properly
但同时
But at the same time
我会留下什么团队投入大量的叉子让guichard的工作充满生机活力
I will leave what team put a lot of fork to make guichard work full of life vibrant
所以按照设计
So by by design
哪些是 rois 不是 ternostic
Which are rois not a ternostic
我们对此遇到了一些问题
And we had a few issues with this
比如委员会的npc有他们自己的生活
For instance , npc from committee have their own life
有时这意味着其中之一
Sometimes it means that one of them
真的很想成为对话行动的一部分
Really wants to be part of the dialogue action
本想做的事,哈哈哈
所以解决方案是在 , 呃周围放置并拒绝区域
So the solution was to put and denied area around the , uh
包含所有内容的对话
Dialogue that contains all the
嗯，演员和摄像机
Um , actors and cameras
但是却让NPSE大吃一惊
but blows the npses
又比如可以打出骑马一样的状态
Another example can be played a state like riding a horse
所以有时在对话开始时
So sometimes at the beginning of the dialogue
假设球员是步行的
Players assumed to be on the foot
所以我们不能在对话开始之前每次都强迫玩家使用这个坐骑
so we cannot force to player to this mount every time before dialogue starts
所以我们将播放一个快捷场景
So instead we'll play a shortcut scene
在显示此安装的戏剧的对话之前
Before the dialogue that shows the play of this mounting
过场动画与对话融为一体的房子
The house that cut scene blends to the dialogue
创建游戏玩法的平滑过渡
Creating a smooth transition from the game play
好的
Okay
现在是最后一部分
And now is that the final part
我将向您展示经过一些改编的对话
I'm going to show you the dialogue with some adaptations
这样你就可以看到所有的功能了，嗯
So you can see all the features , um
但在决赛中它是如何运作的
But how it works in the , in the final
游戏最后的对话
Final dialogue from the game
我希望这会是一个好地方
I hope this will be a good somewhere
让它休息一下
Give it a rest
没有必要谈论你所得到的一切
No point talking about what all you get
愤怒的咯咯声，他们气喘吁吁
Angry gurgles and they puff up
你注意到然后钓鱼
You notice while then fish
那里有黄金吗
Was it the gold there
这里有人发言的人来吧
Anyone here who speaks coming on
呃，他有这种仁慈
Uh , there's this mercy with him
对我来说看起来很珍贵
Looks so dearly to me
他是我招募的唯一一个带领他穿过下水道的人
He's the one recruit of me to show him through the sewers
哦
Oh
在法师那里，引导者知道一点
At the mage , what leads the knows a bit
听到他说话
Heard him talking
无疑
No doubt
我不跟你说话
I don't talk to you
呃，我一直是你的短领带
Uh , i was you constant short tie
我会继续失败，直到我有一个漫长的航行
I'll go on flopping me till me got a long voyage ahead
袖子不是我需要的人，我可以真正与之沟通，这才是我想要的
sleeves not what i need someone i could actually communicate with that's what i want
问候，愧疚记得我
Greetings , guilt remember me
我记得我们是在白果园见面的
I remember we met in white orchard
你要去d路
You're going to road d
也称为主镜
Known also as master mirror
我帮你找到了你的女朋友
I helped you find your gir
我们又见面了，看来你又需要我的帮助了
We meet again and it seems you need my help again
像你一样聆听和放松
heard and loose like you
如果这个苦差事没有先杀死我的话
that is if this slog doesn't kill me you first
还没尝试过
Haven't tried it yet
Em 看起来不太有希望
Em doesn't look promising
和你的情况没什么不同
Not unlike your situation
我可以试着把你从这里救出来，你知道的
I could try to extract you from here , you know
因为你确实想下船，不是吗？
Because you do wish to disembark , do you not
是的，当然，地球上的那个你可以吗？
Yeah , sure , the one on earth could you
哦，比你想象的还要多
Oh , more than you never expect
我会帮你负罪感
I shall help you guilt
但在我这样做之前
But before i do
我必须知道你会回报我
I must know you return the favor
不可能不劳而获
Can't possibly get something for nothing
的确
Indeed
当一切都说完了
When all said and done
我是商人
I am a merchant
那么你需要我的帮助吗
So do you want my help
是的
Yes
这是一笔交易
It's a deal
一旦一切都结束了
Once it's all over
我们将在午夜的十字路口相遇
We shall meet at midnight at the crossroads
遇见扬特拉村附近的柳树
Meet the willows near the village of yantra
啊，我必须给你一些东西来记住我
ah , and i must give you something to remember me by
表明我们是同事的标志是什么
what's that a mark to show we are associates
你在没有人的情况下跟我闲聊吗
Are you gabbing me with no one
哦在灯光下最不温暖b
Oh in the light most not warm b
他们让我的恶魔让我践踏链条
They have my devils make me stomp chain
呃，我们一直在睡觉，度过了整个过程
Uh we've been prime to sleep through the whole thing
你
u
好的
Okay
那么想做什么
So what's the thought of doing
我相信我们的对话系统是成功的
I believe that our dialogue system is a success
我们在没有动画大军的情况下制作了三十五小时的电影内容
We made thirty five hours of cinematic content without army of animatoes
带定制保护套的会议手套
meeting gloves with custom cases
让我们创造出高质量的令人难忘的对话
Allow us to create memorable dialogues with good quality
这帮助我们将存储设置为主要游戏功能
That helped us set storted as a main game feature
因此，它和灵活的对话细节将我们的艺术家提升到一个地方
And so it and flexible dialogue detail boost our artist in one place
每个人都可以从头到尾重现对话
Everyone can recreate dialogue from the beginning to the end
不怎么样，呃，哪个奖项是一个挑战
Not teristic , uh , which award was a challenge
但得益于动态照明等功能
But thanks to the features like dynamic lighting
每个、每个玩家都可以看到自己的版本
Every , every player can see his own version of
呃，对话和故事
Uh , dialogue and story
当然，没有时间做所有事情
And of course there's no time to do everything
我们不得不削减很多功能
We had to cut a lot of features
但我们现在拥有的所有这些未完成的想法和知识
But all this unfinished ideas and knowledge that we have now
我们正在为我们的新游戏使用
We are using for our new game
塞普克二十七十七
Sepk twenty seventy seven
所以如果你想参与其中
So if you like to be part of this
我们很高兴
we are high goes
好的
Okay
所以
so
战斗部分有炸弹
There's a bomb of fight section
你知道，它们将在 gdc Bolt 上提供
You know , on the they will be available on gdc bolt
所以我制作了一堆带有额外细节的视频和幻灯片
So i did a bunch of videos and slides with extra details
所以我们可以以后再做
So we can always be it later
如果你喜欢未来的游戏
And if you like the future game
今年 GDC 还有两场演讲
We have two more presentations of this year gdc
所以你也可以检查一下
So you can check it out as well
仅此而已
And that's all
所以如果您有任何疑问，请拍摄
so if you have any questions like please shoot
和超新星
And supernovo
所以请只问简单的问题
So please ask only simple questions
您展示的工具有多少是第三方的，有多少是内部开发的
How many of the tools that you showed were third party versus developed internally
您有多少工程人员正在开发内部工具
And how much of your engineering staff was developing the internal tools
好的
Okay
所以，嗯，我给你看的所有工具都是现成的，嗯
So , um , all the tools i showed you are made , um
在我们的，呃，红色引擎内部
Internally in our , in our , uh , red engine
所以我们只使用
So we use only
呃，像我的情感这样的额外工具更适合动画和其他东西
Uh , extra tools like my emotion beter for animations and the rest
一切都内置于系统中
Everything is built into the system
即使像屏幕上那样播放，嗯
Even if like the screen play like the , um
甚至喜欢四个工具的效果
Even like the four tool for the effects
一切都集中在我们的细节和工程师身上
And everything is one placed in our , our detail and about the engineers
所以我向你们展示了我们的团队一开始
So i showed you that our team on the , on the beginning
和
and
我们有，呃，三个程序员
We had , uh , three programmers
比如，呃，一名高级人员和，呃，两名专家
Like , uh , one senior and , uh , two specialists
我们必须通过任务创建诸如功能和动画部分以及连接之类的一切
And we had to create everything like features and animation parts and connection through the quest
甚至所有的工具
and even all the tools
所以就像自由人一样
So that are like free people
其余的都是艺术家
And the rest are artists
所以，对话图和时间线
So the , the dialogue graph and the timelines
所有这些都是内部开发的
All of those are internally developed
是的
Yes
一切都只在一个上，呃
Everything is on only one , uh
最好在顶部
Better at the top
是的
Yeah
好的
Okay
嗨，讲得很好
Hi , great talk
一
Um
德国游戏叙事的一个重要部分是，嗯
So big part of the narrative german games is that , um
有些人想跳过对话
Some people want to skip dialogues
ERROR
Um , ha ha
你怎么了，呃
How did you , uh
处理动画未完成等问题
Deal with issues of maybe like animations not finishing
呃，当人们跳过时
Uh , when people skip
好的
Okay
所以，是的
So , yeah
它，当我看到人们都知道跳过对话时，它总是很重要
It , it always heads when i see like the people know skipping the dialogues
我明白其中有一些是你长的。还有，呃
I understand that some of them are you long . and , uh
也许有点太长了
Maybe a little bit too long
一
Um
是的
Yeah
那么从技术角度来说
So from the technical point of view
跳过确实是一个问题，呃
The skipping was a really issue , uh
因为正如我所说，那个对话必须完全是术语性的，呃
Because as i said , that dialog has to be completely terministic , uh
因为当你跳过对话的任何部分时
Because when you skip any part of the dialogue
也许在这一部分中角色和成长项目或做某事
Maybe the in this part character and grow item or do something
稍后你需要拥有它
And later you need to have it
但我们对编辑也有同样的问题
But the same issue we have for the editor
当你按下时，这样做，甚至进行编辑
So doing , even doing the editing , when you press
你可以按，呃，任何部分，任何时间，用
You can press , uh , any section , any time and with
而且你应该有合适的框架
And you should have the proper frame
呃
Uh
所以这几乎是同样的问题
So it's almost the same problem
所以，是的
So , yeah
ERROR
Took a lot of time to
将所有内容写入
To write everything to
去，去拥有它
To , to have it
所以即使从代码的角度来看
So even from the code point of view
那么各个子系统
Then every sub system
呃，必须受时间线控制
Uh , has to be controlled by the timeline
例如在动画中
So in the animations , for example
所以你不能像冷静下来或像你一样
So you cannot have like the cool down or like the u
呃，在动画系统中倾倒
Uh , dumping inside the animation system
ERROR
Because then when you change the part of the dialogue , like in one frame
你会看到这个欺骗
You will see this duping on going down
所以是的
So yeah
是的，这是一个丰富的挑战
It was , it was a a rich challenge
我认为这是
And i think this is
这是程序员要做的任务之一
This is one of the u have this task for programmers to do
谢谢
Thank you
嗨，呃，非常有趣的谈话
Hi , uh , really fascinating talk
非常感谢
Thank you very much
呃，我只是很好奇为什么这些工具看起来非常复杂并且对你们来说非常有用
Uh , i was just curious how these tools seem insanely complex and extremely useful for you guys
呃，开发多久了
Uh , how long into development
你需要让一切正常运转吗
Did it take you to get everything working
或者它只是贯穿整个项目的一个涓滴过程
Or was it just sort of like a trickle process throughout the entire projects
正如我在开头提到的
So as i mentioned at the , at the beginning
我们也为猎魔人提供了对话系统
We had a dialogue system for the witcher too
所以一些工具已经存在了
So some of the tools are already there
比如，呃，图表
Like , uh , the graph , for example
还有画面播放
And the screen play
ERROR
So that is we have to completely right , uh
因为我们有不同的
Because we have the different
你知道，呃，要求
You know , uh , requirements ds
即使存在术语性的东西并且认为如此
Even that there's the terministic stuff and think think so
是的
Yeah
ERROR
Two
那么，好吧
So , okay
所以猛击。因为这个,呃
So bash . because of this , uh
艺术家可以，呃，从一开始就创造一些手指，其下有两个dialoat itor
Artists can could , uh , create some finger from the beginning based on under which are two dialoat itor
然后我们尝试去改进它
And then we try to know improve it
例如，这个，呃，基于动画的外观
So , for example , this , uh , animation based look at
我想我花了大约一年的时间
I think i think it took like the one year to
终于拥有了它，就像
To have it like finally , like
因为我们没有不同的任务和一切
Because we had no different tasks and everything
所以，呵呵
so ,嗯
但我们仍然拥有未来的面貌
But we still have the the looks from the future too
像这样头部在躯干上
Like this for head on torso
所以你可以使用它
So you can use it
稍后你甚至可以切换
And later later you can even switch
是的 。到、到、到新的
Yeah . to , to the , to the new ones
非常感谢
Thank you very much
嗨，呃，我是丹尼斯·普罗格拉斯·格林
Hi , uh , i'm dennis prograss green
呃，我有一个关于声音设计的问题
Uh , i have a question about the sound design
呃
Uh
所以你不太了解
So you didn't know a lot about
声音和对话是如何设置的
How the sound and the dialogue was set up
呃
Uh
我的意思是三个 d 参数
I mean the three d parameters
呃，音量等等
Uh , volume and so on
呃，你之前也是这么做的
Uh , so did you do it and before
之前，呃，在某些特定的第三方环境中
Before , uh , in some specific third party environment
或者您让声音设计师设计声音参数
Or you let your sound designers to design the sound parameters
就在编辑器里
Just in the editor
当他们设计对话框时
When they design the dialog
好的
Okay
老实说，我不确定
So honestly , i'm not sure
因为这部分就像声音设计一样
Because this part is like the the sound design is
对我来说这将是一个谜
It will be between like the mystery for me
呃
Uh
我认为他们可以创造，呃
I think they can they create , uh
哦，呃
Oh , uh
这里应该有某个地方
There should be somewhere here
我是一些设计
I was some design
好的
Okay
呃
Uh
但是，嗯
But , um
我想，呃，他们创造了自己的声音，呃，sso
I think , uh , they create a sound of their own , uh , sso
您可以放置​​声音事件等事件
You can put events like sound events
而且，你知道，在声音时间线上做一些、一些简单的事情
And , you know , do some , some simple stuff on the timeline of sound
但资产是根据洞察力制作的
But the assets are made like on the insight
所以这确实意味着你不要太执着于这三个 d 员工。等等
So does mean that you don't stick too much to this three d staff . and so on
我的意思是如果你移动相机
I mean that if you move the camera
声音没有变化
The sound is not changing
呃
Uh
好的
Okay
所以你有几个选项来指定这个，呃
So you had a few options to specify this , uh
您可以附加到
You can attach to the
嗯，声音监听者
Um , the sound listener
让我们对相机或角色说
Let's say to the camera or to the characters
但老实说，我，我，我不确定它是如何完成的
But honestly , i , i , i'm not sure how would how it's done
就像，呃，在幕后
And like , uh , under the hood
那么，好吧
So , okay
非常感谢你的出色狗
Thank you very much for brilliant dog
太感谢了
Thank you so much
嗯，嗨
Um , hi
很棒的演讲
Great talk
呃，你们真的从bioware中得到了启发
Uh , you guys are really inspiring from bioware
所以你们现在正在跟我们争夺我们的钱
So you guys are giving us a run for our money right now
原来如此，太好了
So it's , it's great
一
Um
您对 vo 的依赖程度如何
How dependent are you on vo
比如你什么时候有tts之类的
Like when do you have tts has or something
当你在等待它到来时
While you're waiting for that to come in
或者像配音一样真实
Or it's true like vovoiceover
喜欢演技，喜欢
Like the acting , like
在你得到它之前你不努力吗
Do you not work on it until you get it
或者你喜欢文字转语音吗
Or do you tps or like text to speech
是的
Yeah
一
Um
好的
Okay
所以我希望有这样的，呃
So i hope there there be as this , uh
奖金幻灯片部分有关此内容的简短部分
Short part of about this in bonus slide section
但基本上你有两种不同的，呃，方法
But basically you have two different , uh , ways
您可以指定保存者
You can specify the preservers
您可以作为设计师录制零自我的配音
You can record voice over zero self as a designer
所以你可以使用麦克风
So you can using microphone
你有声音
And you have the voice over
不幸的是我减少了那么多。因为没有
I unfortunately reduce it that much . because no
他们，他们想听到你知道的，他们的声音
They , they want to hear you know , their voices
所以第二个选择，我们可以使用文本转语音
So a second option , we can use text to speech
所以我们可以根据文本生成
So we can generate the based on the text
我们可以生成 , 声音 fink
We can generate the , the sound fink
哪个是基地
Which is a base
它主要用于，嗯，用于对话的时间安排
It was used mostly that , um , for the thing that you have the timing for the dialogue
稍后当你从光环中获得决赛或服务器时
And later when you have the final or servers from the auras
你可以，呃，你可以把它
You can , uh , you can put it
是的
Yeah
但是，呃，有时这意味着，嗯
But , uh , sometimes it means that , um
你需要一个额外的步骤来润色对话
You need to have one extra step for polishing the dialogue
当你得到最后的配音时
When you have the final voicovers
所以有时这是一个问题
So sometimes it was the issue
尤其是对于怪物来说
Especially that for the monster
例如
For example
有很多，呃
There are a lot of , uh
对声音进行后期处理
Post processes on the , on the voices
所以有时候你可以听到回声或者其他什么
So sometimes you could the echo or something
所以，嗯，，，持续时间
So , um , the , the duration of the
呃，对话就像是，正在增长
Uh , of the dialogue is like , is growing
所以我们需要喜欢
So we need to like
我们确保稍后一切都正确进行
We make sure that everything is pread properly later also
再次感谢您
Thank you again
感谢您精彩的讲座
Thank you for the awesome lecture
呃，我的问题是关于唇形同步的，呃
Uh , my question is about actually lip sync , uh
不在于短语长度
Not in terms of the phrase length
ERROR
But in terms of the articulation
它是如何制作的
How was it made
一
Um
所以我们用在唇部水槽
So we use for the lips sink
我们用了不软，呃
We used unnot soft , uh
后面有一个选择标签
A select tag behind it
呃，当然我们根据语言版本有不同的省略形式
Uh , of course we have different ellipsing by language version
而且，呃，你有一个小特征
And , uh , you had a small features that
在唇部开始之前，角色应该吸一口气或者做一些小细节之类的事情
Before the lipson start character should take a breath or something like a small detail
呃
Uh
有时可见，有时不取决于对话，嗯
Sometimes the visible , sometimes it's not depends on the on the dialogue , um
但是嘴唇，嗯，正在闯入时尚排放系统
But the lipsis , um , is breaking into the fashion emission system
所以当你有了，呃，渔唇的最终动画后
So when you have the , uh , final animation for the , for the fisher lips
ERROR
Things can like override some of the parts
而且，你知道，并且很好地融入其中
And , you know , and blend nicely into this
还有，嗯
And , um
所以你仍然可以微笑、交谈或类似的事情
So you still can have like a smile and talking or something like this
但配音呢
But what about the voiceover
ERROR
Does it analyze the voice
是的
And yeah
Yeah
所以我不是，呃，我不是
So that i'm not , uh , i'm not
ERROR
So works like this that you need to put the as input , uh , text text
呃呃，声音像波浪一样
Uh , uh , voice over like the wave
并生成曲线，呃
And generates the curves , uh
每条曲线都像
And every curve is like the the
呃，面部帖子
Uh , the facial post
所以后来我们把它融入到法律的细节中
So later we blend it into the legallic in our detail
我们将其混合。或者，你知道，我们将它混合起来
We blend it . or , you know , we gain blend it
呃，动态地带有一些额外的功能
Uh , dynamically with some extra features
因为您还可以对 、 面部动画进行修正
Because you can have also the corrections for the , for the facial animation
所以我们有很多没有输入
So we have a lot of no input
然后我们喜欢把它混合在一处
Then we like mix it in one place
并且，并且，呃，通常是最后的
And , and , uh , generally the final
基于骨骼的面部动画形成
The formation based on the bones for the facial animation
谢谢
Thank you
嗯，我对你们使用的预构建手势动画有一个疑问
Um , i've quite had a question about the pre build gesture animations you guys used
你是在对话脚本编写之前还是之后创建的，呃
Did you create them before the dialogue script was written or afterwards , uh
ERROR
Most cases afterwards ? because the , as i said that the diagresis
我喜欢，我喜欢导演
I like , i like directors
所以我们有脚本
So we have the script
呃
Uh
ERROR
You can also , of course you have to corporate with the
呃，四方设计师和作家一样
Uh , quad designers and like the writers
但你知道，你需要弄清楚如何做
But you need to figure out how to , you know
在 ，在 ，在好中创建这个对话
Create this dialogue in , in , in good
嗯，很好
Uh , in good way
所以有时这意味着您可以请求特殊的，呃，对话动画
So sometimes it means that you can request the special , uh , dialoc animation
因为没有它真的很难创造
And because like it really very hard to create without it
但在大多数情况下他们会尝试这样做，你知道的
But in most cases they try to , you know
他们尽可能多地使用，比如，你知道的
They use as much as possible , like , you know
他们谦虚地施展许多魔法
They do a lot of magic modeously
就像，呃
Like , uh
有时他们只需几个手势和智能相机
Sometimes they from the only a few gestures and of smart camera
你知道，嗯，开枪
You know , um , shots
他们创造了非常好的表演
They create a really good performance
谢谢
Thank you
乌塔斯蒂克狗
Utastic dog
非常感谢你的，它真的很鼓舞人心
Thank you very much for the for it it's really inspiring
我的问题是同样的
My question was along the same lines
但我想知道你是如何组织点击的
But i was wondering how did you manage to organize hits
所以有这么多片
So having so many pieces
并且动画师之间的工作不会过多
And not overwhopping work between animators
并确保您拥有所需的一切
And making sure that you have everything that you need
他使用的一般管道是什么
What was the general pipeline that he used
所以 Epipeline 与我向你展示的非常相似
So epipeline was very similar that i , i showed you
所以就像对话后面的描述一样
So it goes like the descript later the the dialogue
所以使用生殖器总是可以非常快地创造
So using the genital can always create very fast
就像迭代的第一段对话
Like the first dialogue of iteration
所以我们完全可以设计并将其放入游戏中
So we can quite design is put it into the game
这样我们就可以玩了，你知道的
So we can play , you know
看看热战和，嗯
And check out it hot wars and the , um
他们会是什么样子
How they're going look like with this
后来设计师可以，你知道，创造，嗯
And later that that designers can , you know , on create , um
视觉部分最后
The final of visual parts
或者他们可以请求资产，比如，好吧
Or they can request assets like , okay
我们需要有一个特殊的效果
We need to have like a special effect
所以请这样做。或者我们需要有特殊的声音或其他东西
So please do it . or we need to have special sounds or something
所以后来我们有了这个
So later that we have this
而这个制作人的制作人
And that the producer producer for this
你知道，他们收集所有的小任务
And you know , they collect and all the small tasks
我知道并要求不同
And i know and request for different
所以基本上
So basically
所以基本上这就像一个迭代过程
So basically it was like an iterative process
你用你拥有的东西工作
You work with what you have
如果你需要什么
And if you need something
是的
Yeah
我们有很多是的
We have a lot of yeah
你有很多版本
You have a lot of erations
即使对话就像，呃
Even if the dialogues like , uh
这不像对话完成的那样
It's not like the dialogues done
计算完成
And it's compulated done
因为即使有组织
Because even with the organization
你需要返回每种语言
You need to go back for every language
并检查是否对于每种语言
And check if for every language
一切都好
Everything is okay
所以总是很费时间
So it's always time consuming
所以有时候你需要知道扭曲
So sometimes you need to know twist
有些人认为是因为语言版本不同
Some think because of the different language version
因为希望每种语言版本都有相同的质量。当然
Because would like to have the same quality for for each language version . of course
是的
Yeah
所以最终结果是这样，呃
So it's end up that even , uh
你可以，你可以有不同的，呃，时间线版本
You could , you could have different , uh , timeline version
不同，呃，语言版本的一部分
Part of different , uh , language version
如果如果你想要的话
If if you want
所以默认情况下像这样，像这样
So by defaults like this , like this
你可以缩放它
You can scale it
但如果你真的想改变它
But if you really want to , to to change it
有一个选项你可以说，好吧
There is option that you can say , okay
例如，对于法语，我想知道移动安全位
For example , for french , i would like to know to move safety bit
全部额外收费。呃呃。细节
All at extra . uuuh . details
因为我们，我们不
Because we , we don't
我们不使用数据库
We don't use db
所以这就是
So this was the , the , the , the
嗯，来自亚洲的羽毛箱
Um , plumatic case from from asia
但在同一个
But in the same
但在同一个你
But in the same u
同一时间。这没有什么好处
The same time . this there are few benefits from this
因为我们可以看到演员真实的表演
Because we can have the real performance from the actors
因此，在某些语言中，您可以自定义笑话
So in some languages you can have the the custom letting jokes
因为你知道这个笑话可以更长，因为它
Because you know that the joke can be like longer because it's
我知道它是用不同语言表示的波兰语
I know it's in polish on different language
所以有，有一些好处
So there are , there are some benefits
还有谢谢你
And the thank you
我认为是
I think it's
好的
Okay
是的
Yeah
您可以随时回答任何其他问题
You're done any , any time for any more questions
好的
Okay
所以你也可以，我们可以，我们现在就可以去问问是否可以
So you can also , we can , we can go here and now and ask if okay
所以程序非常感谢
So program thank you very much